<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-15T18:04:44-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/</id><title type="html">Open New York</title><subtitle>New Yorkers for more housing</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/jekyll/update/2018/05/10/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-05-10T23:19:18-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-10T23:19:18-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/jekyll/update/2018/05/10/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/jekyll/update/2018/05/10/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Not-So-Strange Bedfellows</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/jekyll/update/2018/05/10/learning-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Not-So-Strange Bedfellows" /><published>2018-05-10T16:51:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-10T16:51:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/jekyll/update/2018/05/10/learning-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/jekyll/update/2018/05/10/learning-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;This post is a test. I am going to link to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opennewyork.city/&quot; title=&quot;Open New York, a fantastic organization&quot;&gt;a thing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-happened-in-thailand&quot;&gt;What happened in Thailand?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October 1973, a popular uprising in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thailand&quot; title=&quot;Thailand - Wikipedia, the Free Encylopedia&quot;&gt;Thailand&lt;/a&gt;, led by student activists and supported by a broad spectrum of Bangkok’s residents, successfully brought an end to a military regime. Once again in May 1992, it seemed that much the same story unfolded in the streets of the capital, as a far larger and more politically conscious middle class—the “mobile phone mob”, as they were called—was at the forefront of protests to end yet another military regime and restore democracy. To many observers, the 1992 crisis seemed to herald the political coming of age of the generation that had led the 1973 protests as politically engaged urban middle class, primarily at the expense of the military and government bureaucracy that had dominated Thai politics for the previous six decades. This, for many, seemed usher in a truly transformative process, one that culminated in the promulgation of a new constitution in 1997—popularly termed the “People’s Constitution”— considered to be the most liberal in the country’s history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;then-what-happened&quot;&gt;Then what happened?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But less than a decade after the 1997 constitution came into force, any hopes for a new age of Thai democracy had been shattered by a military coup in 2006, following widespread protests against the populist government of Thaksin Shinawatra, who had risen to dominate the post-1997 political landscape. After a brief period of military rule, the pro-Thaksin coalition regained power under a succession of short-lived premiers, before falling to the pressures of court bans and further mass protests and losing power to the opposition in 2008.Thaksin’s sister Yingluck was able to secure a majority in the 2011 elections, but her government was deposed in yet another coup last year, once again following months of protests essentially calling for one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;and-then-what&quot;&gt;And then what?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The composition of the anti-Thaksin coalitions in 2006, 2008, and 2014, when compared to those opposing the military in 1973 and 1992, seems fairly shocking at first glance—for they largely overlap. The primary base of the anti-Thaksin protests were also the members of the urban middle classes, Indeed, many of the very same figures who had condemned military rule in prior decades in many cases now called for it in all but name, if not openly. People who had once taken to the streets calling for and popular government and electoral democracy now demanded an unelected “reform council” while attempting to prevent an election from taking place! Long-time critics of the military and royalist establishments seemed to have united with them in opposing the elected government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-role-of-sarit&quot;&gt;The role of Sarit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;A random photo of the George Washington Bridge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&quot;above-is-a-wholly-unrelated-if-striking-photograph-of-the-george-washington-bridge&quot;&gt;Above is a wholly unrelated, if striking, photograph of the George Washington Bridge.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarit revived the monarchy’s status in society, using it to support his agenda of &lt;em&gt;phatthana&lt;/em&gt; (development), as King Bhumibol began his famous tours of the countryside, with the aim of forging a close link between the monarchy and a rural population long ignored by Bangkok governments (Kershaw 2001, 137). As the process of economic development led to the emergence of drastic changes to Thai society, the monarchy proved adept at legitimizing such changes and new classes of society—in particular the hitherto “alien” Sino-Thai merchant class—by extending over them its royal charisma, or &lt;em&gt;barami&lt;/em&gt;, through royal patronage or ritual merit-making ceremonies, through which the monarchy was also able to build a substantial financial reserve, reducing its operational dependence on the government of the day (Connors 2011, 659).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite Sarit’s death in 1963 and the return of Thanom (this time propped up by Field Marshal Praphas Charusathian, Commander-in-Chief of the Army) to the premiership, business, particularly the service sector, expanded at a brisk pace, people in the countryside flocked to the cities, particularly Bangkok, and the educational sector grew rapidly, if erratically (Chaloemtiarana 1979, 227). By 1972, over 100,000 students were enrolled in universities, compared to just 18,000 nine years prior (Jäger 2012, 1141). This necessitated correspondingly tremendous growth in the number of academics and administrative works, as well as positions to absorb this newly university-educated generation; the number of administrative workers and government officials, according to census figures, grew by &lt;strong&gt;over 840%&lt;/strong&gt; between 1960 and 1970 (Ockey 1999, 235).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;apotheosis-of-the-monarchy&quot;&gt;Apotheosis of the monarchy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.thetimes.co.uk/imageserver/image/methode%2Ftimes%2Fprod%2Fweb%2Fbin%2Fee2dec1e-9150-11e6-91d4-91c7eaaf09d6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;King Bhumibol and Queen Sirikit&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;King Bhumibol and Queen Sirikit, the daughter of a Thai diplomat whom he met while her father (himself a member of the royal family) was ambassador to London.&lt;/em&gt; (GETTY IMAGES)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BUT&lt;/strong&gt; perhaps even more than the potential threats posed by dissidents and insurgents to their economic interests, what unsettled the middle classes most deeply was the threat posed to the monarchy. Ever since the revival of the monarchy’s stature under Sarit, the monarchy had gradually returned to its prior position in Thai society. For the middle classes in particular, as Anderson described it, it had&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[become] both a talisman and a moral alibi. The historical depth and solidity of the institution appeared as a kind of charm against disorder and disintegration … members of the middle strata felt their nationalist self-esteem morally guaranteed by their loyalty to the throne, the epitome of the national heritage. Thus any assault, however, indirect, on the legitimacy of the throne was necessarily sensed as a menace to that alibi. (Anderson 1977, 23)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monarchy thus simultaneously stood for order and change, tradition and progress, and reconciled any tension between such concepts, a tension that would otherwise be felt the most strongly by the new middle classes. As a result, it would be necessary to defend the monarchy—a drive that would come to figure greatly in the present political crisis—against those that would seek to undermine it. Its most vociferous defenders would be the new middle classes, who, after the events of October 1973 and October 1976 had exposed both their economic and social vulnerabilities, had “forged a new sense of horizontal solidarity” that would continue to strengthen over the next decade and a half (Tsuruyo and Kagoya 2003, 245).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kyle Dontoh</name></author><summary type="html">This post is a test. I am going to link to a thing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Does Building More Homes Keep Housing Affordable?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/2018/05/10/How-Does-Building-More-Homes-Keep-Housing-Affordable_.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Does Building More Homes Keep Housing Affordable?" /><published>2018-05-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/2018/05/10/How%20Does%20Building%20More%20Homes%20Keep%20Housing%20Affordable_</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/test_blog_mk_2/2018/05/10/How-Does-Building-More-Homes-Keep-Housing-Affordable_.html">&lt;p&gt;Many people often ask our members how building “luxury” condos or other market-rate housing would help solve the housing crisis in New York City, since they are usually priced far above what the ordinary person can afford, let alone low-income renters or other marginalized groups. To many, if not most people, the most obvious way of increasing the amount of affordable housing is to simply “build more affordable houses”, and that a strategy of increasing housing supply at the upper end of the market &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/urban-myth-busting-new-rental-housing-and-median-income-households/&quot;&gt;would only help drive up prices further&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the answer to this apparent dilemma is perhaps even simpler than the question: right now, there are simply fewer houses in New York City then there are people who want to rent or buy them. New York City has added over 1.1 million jobs since 1991 but only  488,000 housing units over the same time period. This makes what would otherwise be normal housing pricey, luxury housing expensive, and truly upscale housing outrageous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lack of choice means that more people are competing for the same limited options. For example, a $3,000/month apartment might find itself bid upon by two roommates hoping to split it for $1,500/month each and by a somewhat more established professional looking to make an upgrade for a little more space–and who has a little more money to spare. It is in precisely a case like this where building more housing, even at market rates, would make a critical difference. If the professional looking to rent for $3,000/month has the option of renting or buying a new luxury apartment in their price range, she would probably do so, freeing up the existing apartment for the two roommates to rent at an affordable price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long run, even housing once considered “luxury” might contribute to the stock of affordable housing by &lt;a href=&quot;http://cityobservatory.org/what-filtering-can-and-cant-do/ /&quot;&gt;a process known as filtering&lt;/a&gt;. Since affluent homeowners often tend to seek the the most up-to-date amenities and top-of-the-line finishes in their homes (as can be evinced by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.curbed.com/2018/3/7/17087588/home-renovation-unnecessary-mcmansion-hell-wagner&quot;&gt;proliferation of home renovation shows on cable TV&lt;/a&gt;), they will, in a market with sufficient supply, naturally gravitate towards apartments in new buildings. The old apartments they leave behind may then be subdivided or split amongst roommates at a lower price, turning luxury to affordable. We can recognize this process at work in the sale of new cars or cellphones, which actively reduce the price of older iterations. A healthy market for homes would function similarly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not enough housing is built, however, as is presently the case, then the opposite will happen–and &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; happening now in New York and places across the country. What was once affordable housing will eventually &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nydailynews.com/life-style/real-estate/nyc-developers-reinventing-old-tenements-hip-homes-article-1.1983415&quot;&gt;come to be defined as luxury housing&lt;/a&gt;, and we will be left with increasingly absurd cases such as two bedroom houses in the &lt;em&gt;suburbs&lt;/em&gt; of the Bay Area &lt;a href=&quot;https://sf.curbed.com/2018/3/2/17073100/silicon-valley-house-home-sunnyvale-record-price-crisis&quot;&gt;being sold for $2 million after just days on the market&lt;/a&gt;. There are no shortage of only slightly less ridiculous cases here in New York, and this is this trend we seek to reverse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also worth noting that the term “luxury housing” is somewhat misleading. It is increasingly the case (if not uniformly so) that “luxury housing” is &lt;a href=&quot;https://artplusmarketing.com/market-rate-housing-isnt-a-bad-word-and-we-won-t-solve-the-housing-crisis-without-it-ce67c06aff4d&quot;&gt;now applied to mean any sort of market-rate development&lt;/a&gt;, whereas “affordable housing” refers strictly to subsidized below-market-rate development. In this case we are left with a missing middle, whereby developers are target the upper end or, more rarely, the lower end of the market but the vast middle of would-be homeowners and renters are generally left uncatered to. The result is most of us search for apartments in older buildings rather than new ones, which is why increasing the affordability of  the existing housing stock would have the greatest impact for the middle class and the vast majority of New Yorkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While programs like Mandatory Inclusionary Housing, and the 421-a tax credit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www1.nyc.gov/assets/hpd/downloads/pdf/about/hny-2.pdf&quot;&gt;sometimes seek to target middle-income earners&lt;/a&gt;, the number units they add is far below what is necessary to make a meaningful impact on the New York housing market. Even the ambitious targets set by the de Blasio Administration &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.city-journal.org/html/de-blasio%E2%80%99s-misguided-housing-plan-11655.html&quot;&gt;would not be able to make a dent in the housing shortage&lt;/a&gt; currently affecting our city. On the other hand, it has been found that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lao.ca.gov/Publications/Report/3345&quot;&gt;increasing the supply of market-rate housing increases affordability&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;even for low income earners&lt;/em&gt;, and that &lt;a href=&quot;http://gawker.com/study-building-luxury-housing-for-gentrifiers-helps-th-1758724083&quot;&gt;housing prices increase less rapidly for everyone&lt;/a&gt; when more housing units are added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we must look to private development to make the biggest contribution towards housing affordable for all New Yorkers, and this is why we have taken the strategy that we have. When applied on a large-scale, this principle would help keep prices down for the ordinary New Yorker, and keep this city affordable and accessible for everyone–paving the way to a more open New York.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kyle Dontoh</name></author><summary type="html">Many people often ask our members how building “luxury” condos or other market-rate housing would help solve the housing crisis in New York City, since they are usually priced far above what the ordinary person can afford, let alone low-income renters or other marginalized groups. To many, if not most people, the most obvious way of increasing the amount of affordable housing is to simply “build more affordable houses”, and that a strategy of increasing housing supply at the upper end of the market would only help drive up prices further.</summary></entry></feed>